Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到 EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是 Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是 Erika。
And today we're bringing you part two of the presidential farewell speech of President
今天我们要带来总统告别演说的第二部分，来自
Eisenhower.
艾森豪威尔总统。
That's right.
没错。
So, we saw in a previous lesson the beginning of this speech.
我们在上一课中看到了这个演说的开头部分。
Now we're going to look towards the end of the speech.
现在我们要看看演说的结尾部分。
Now, we must tell you as well that we did change the speech a little bit, right?
我们得告诉你，我们对演说做了一点改动，对吧？
We changed it a little bit to make it a little bit more comprehensible and also we did shorten
我们稍微改动了一下，让它更容易理解，而且我们也缩短了
it.
它。
We didn't make it this short.
我们没有把它缩得这么短。
We did take out a lot of stuff.
我们确实删掉了很多内容。
All right.
好的。
So, again, Marco, why are we looking at this speech?
那么，再次问一下，Marco，我们为什么要看这个演说？
What are we learning from it?
我们从中学到了什么？
Well, in this last part of the presidential farewell speech, there are a lot of great
嗯，在这篇总统告别演说的最后部分，有很多很棒的
words that are more difficult and very poetic.
词汇，它们比较难，而且非常富有诗意。
So you can use them in different formal circumstances or just to sound a little bit more well-spoken.
所以你可以在不同的正式场合使用它们，或者只是为了听起来更有口才。
Yeah.
是的。
And we also, again, are going to look at some really quite difficult and challenging structures
而且我们还要再次看看一些非常难且具有挑战性的结构，
that we hope you can use maybe when you're giving a formal talk or even in your writing
希望你在做正式演讲时，甚至是在写作中，如果想听起来很专业，
if you want to sound quite professional.
可以用上它们。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So, why don't we listen to the dialogue for the first time?
那么，我们为什么不先听一遍对话呢？
Let's listen how President Eisenhower says goodbye and then we'll come back and look
让我们听听艾森豪威尔总统是如何告别的，然后我们再回来看
at the words.
这些词汇。
We now stand ten years past the midpoint of a century that has witnessed four major wars
我们现在站在本世纪中点过去十年的位置，这个世纪见证了四次主要战争
among great nations.
在大国之间。
Three of these involved our own country.
其中三次涉及我们自己的国家。
Despite the carnage of these conflicts, America is today the strongest, the most influential,
尽管这些冲突造成了屠杀，但美国今天是世界上最强大、最有影响力、
and the most productive nation in the world.
和最高产的国家。
We are understandably proud of this preeminence, yet we realize that America's leadership and
我们理所当然地为这种卓越感到自豪，然而我们意识到美国的领导力和
prestige depend not merely upon our unmatched material progress, riches, and military strength,
声望不仅取决于我们无与伦比的物质进步、财富和军事实力，
but on how we use our power in the interests of world peace and human betterment.
还取决于我们如何为了世界和平和人类福祉使用我们的力量。
Throughout America's adventure in free government, such basic purposes have been to keep the
在美国自由政府的冒险历程中，这些基本目标一直是维护
peace, to foster progress and human achievement, and to enhance liberty, dignity, and integrity
和平、促进进步和人类成就，以及增强自由、尊严和正直
among peoples and among nations.
在人民和国家之间。
We pray that peoples of all faiths, all races, all nations may have their great human needs
我们祈祷所有信仰、所有种族、所有国家的人民都能满足他们伟大的人类需求，
satisfied, that those now denied opportunity shall come to enjoy it to the full, that all
那些现在被剥夺机会的人能够充分享受它，所有
who yearn for freedom may experience its spiritual blessings, that those who have freedom will
渴望自由的人能体验其精神祝福，那些拥有自由的人
understand also its heavy responsibilities, that all who are insensitive to the needs
也能理解其沉重的责任，所有对他人的需求
of others will learn charity, that the scourges of poverty, disease, and ignorance will be
漠不关心的人将学会慈善，贫困、疾病和无知的祸害将
made to disappear from the earth, and that in the goodness of time, all peoples will
从地球上消失，并且在时间的恩赐中，所有人民将
come to live together in a peace guaranteed by the binding force of mutual respect and
在由相互尊重和爱的约束力保证的和平中共同生活。
love.
Now, on Friday noon, I am to become a private citizen.
现在，在周五中午，我将成为一名普通公民。
I am proud to do so.
我为此感到自豪。
I look forward to it.
我期待着它。
Thank you and good night.
谢谢你们，晚安。
Well, that certainly was a very moving speech, hey?
嗯，那确实是一个非常感人的演讲，对吧？
Very moving and to a certain point, a little bit religious, huh?
非常感人，而且在某种程度上，有点宗教色彩，嗯？
Yeah, I think we'll talk a little bit about that a little bit later, but let's concentrate
是的，我想我们稍后会讨论一下这一点，但现在让我们集中
on the language now.
在语言上。
So we'll go to Language Takeaway.
所以我们将进入语言要点部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, on Language Takeaway today, we'll start with our first word and it's preeminence.
好的，在今天的语言要点中，我们从第一个词开始，它是 preeminence。
All right, we are understandably proud of this preeminence.
好的，我们理所当然地为这种卓越感到自豪。
A preeminence.
卓越。
So preeminence, what is this?
那么 preeminence，这是什么？
Basically, it's the state of being the leader of something.
基本上，它是成为某事物领导者的状态。
Okay, so in this case, America was the preeminent nation.
好的，所以在这种情况下，美国是卓越的国家。
Right, so they were coming up, they were very prosperous, so they had a preeminence in the
对，所以他们崛起，非常繁荣，所以在世界上拥有
world.
卓越地位。
All right, so I think we can see here, you can use this as an adjective, a preeminent
好的，所以我想我们可以看到，你可以把它用作形容词，一个卓越的
nation, or as a noun, an uncountable noun, the preeminence of our state.
国家，或者作为名词，一个不可数名词，我们州的卓越地位。
Very good.
非常好。
Since we can use this word as a noun and an adjective, why don't we listen to some more
既然我们可以把这个词用作名词和形容词，我们为什么不听一些
examples so we can get a better understanding of it?
例子，以便更好地理解它呢？
Example one.
例子一。
Now, please welcome Dr. Frank Hicks, the world's most preeminent expert on nuclear biology.
现在，请欢迎 Frank Hicks 博士，世界上最卓越的核生物学专家。
Example two.
例子二。
He's been a leader in his field for 25 years and his preeminence has never been questioned.
他在自己的领域里当了25年的领导者，他的卓越地位从未受到质疑。
Example three.
例子三。
Carol Dixon is one of the most preeminent experts in green technology.
Carol Dixon 是绿色技术领域最卓越的专家之一。
All right, well, Eisenhower was talking about all of the things that the American people
好的，艾森豪威尔在谈论美国人民自成为自由国家以来所做的
had done since they became a free nation, and one of these things was to foster progress
所有事情，其中之一就是促进进步
in human achievement.
在人类成就方面。
Foster progress in human achievement.
促进人类成就的进步。
Well, I like this verb a lot, to foster something.
嗯，我很喜欢这个动词，to foster something。
So if I say to foster progress or to foster something, what am I saying?
所以如果我说促进进步或培养某物，我在说什么？
To help something grow and develop.
帮助某物成长和发展。
To take care of it, to nurse it.
照顾它，培育它。
Yeah.
是的。
And we commonly hear this word associated with children, right?
我们经常听到这个词与孩子相关，对吧？
A foster child.
一个寄养孩子。
Yeah.
是的。
So what's that?
那是什么？
If you have a foster child, you are basically taking care of a child because the parents
如果你有一个寄养孩子，你基本上是在照顾一个孩子，因为父母
can't look after them.
无法照顾他们。
It's not like adopting because you don't actually, it's not actually legal.
这不像是收养，因为你实际上没有，实际上不合法。
It's just that you're helping somebody out by raising this child.
只是你在通过抚养这个孩子来帮助别人。
Right.
对。
So we can see the connection there, a foster child to foster something.
所以我们可以看到其中的联系，寄养孩子和培养某物。
But you know, this is really a great word and I think it would help to give a couple
但你知道，这真的是一个很棒的词，我认为给几个
of examples of how we could use it.
例子来说明如何使用它会很有帮助。
So for example, I can say, our company is looking to foster better creativity in the
所以例如，我可以说，我们公司希望在工作场所培养更好的创造力。
workplace.
Or we could say, here at Praxis Language, we foster the development of your English.
或者我们可以说，在 Praxis Language，我们培养你英语的发展。
Very good.
非常好。
So the word foster.
所以这个词是 foster。
Now moving on, in his speech, he was talking about nations and faiths and different types
现在继续，在他的演讲中，他谈到了国家、信仰和不同类型的
of groups and he said, all who yearn for freedom.
群体，他说，所有渴望自由的人。
All right.
好的。
This is a great phrase.
这是一个很棒的短语。
All who yearn for freedom.
所有渴望自由的人。
To yearn.
渴望。
So to yearn for something.
所以渴望某物。
Now if I yearn for freedom or I yearn for something, it's basically that I really want
现在如果我渴望自由或渴望某物，基本上是我从心底里非常想要
it in my heart.
它。
Yeah, you really wish for it in a way that's almost, almost painful.
是的，你以一种几乎痛苦的方式非常希望得到它。
You know, you want it so badly.
你知道，你非常想要它。
Now you wouldn't say like, I'm yearning for ice cream, would you?
现在你不会说，我渴望冰淇淋，对吧？
No, unless you were locked up in prison and hadn't had ice cream for 55 years.
不会，除非你被关在监狱里，55年没吃过冰淇淋。
Exactly.
正是。
So it's usually related to something that's very difficult to get or something like freedom
所以它通常与很难得到的东西有关，比如自由
or yearning for.
或渴望。
That's really important.
那真的很重要。
Exactly.
正是。
Something very important.
非常重要的事情。
And now for our last word, President Eisenhower was talking about charity.
现在来看我们的最后一个词，艾森豪威尔总统谈到了慈善。
He was talking about freedom and he mentioned the scourges of poverty.
他谈到了自由，并提到了贫困的祸害。
Okay.
好的。
So scourges.
所以祸害。
The scourges of poverty.
贫困的祸害。
Scourges is a really difficult but interesting word.
Scourges 是一个很难但有趣的词。
So why don't we hear a few more examples to help us understand it.
所以我们为什么不听几个例子来帮助我们理解它。
Example one.
例子一。
Malaria is a disease that continues to be a scourge to the developing world.
疟疾是一种继续成为发展中国家祸害的疾病。
Example two.
例子二。
One day we hope to eliminate the scourge of cancer.
有一天我们希望消除癌症的祸害。
Example three.
例子三。
NATO promises to wipe out the scourge of terrorism.
北约承诺消除恐怖主义的祸害。
So as we can see, the scourges of something basically is the cause of pain or suffering.
所以我们可以看到，某物的祸害基本上是指痛苦或苦难的根源。
So now relating it back to the text, we see scourges of poverty.
所以现在回到文本，我们看到贫困的祸害。
Yeah, scourges of poverty, scourges of disease, and scourges of ignorance.
是的，贫困的祸害、疾病的祸害和无知的祸害。
All right.
好的。
So we can see that poverty, ignorance, and disease cause a lot of really terrible things,
所以我们可以看到贫困、无知和疾病导致了很多非常可怕的事情，
right?
对吧？
Exactly.
正是。
So that's why we say they are scourges.
所以这就是为什么我们说它们是祸害。
Okay.
好的。
So scourges.
所以祸害。
So that brings us to the end of our words for takeaway today.
这就把我们带到了今天词汇要点的结尾。
But as we talked about earlier, we've got some really difficult and interesting structures
但正如我们之前谈到的，我们现在有一些非常难且有趣的结构
to look at now in Fluency Builder.
要在流利度构建部分看。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
Okay.
好的。
So in Fluency Builder, we'll start off with the very first sentence of the paragraph.
所以在流利度构建中，我们从段落的第一句话开始。
When he said, we now stand 10 years past the midpoint of a century.
当他说，我们现在站在本世纪中点过去十年的位置。
Okay.
好的。
So I love this phrase.
所以我喜欢这个短语。
We now stand 10 years past the midpoint of the century.
我们现在站在本世纪中点过去十年的位置。
Now it's interesting because he is making reference to the future in the present.
这很有趣，因为他是在用现在时提到未来。
And he's using a great phrase to do that.
他用了一个很棒的短语来做这个。
We now stand.
我们现在站在。
Now we can change it a little bit and use the first part, we now stand in different
现在我们可以稍微改变一下，在不同的情况下使用第一部分，
circumstances.
我们现在站在。
So why don't we listen to a couple of examples.
所以我们为什么不听几个例子。
Example one.
例子一。
We now stand before you to declare our love and be united in marriage.
我们现在站在你们面前，宣布我们的爱，并结为夫妻。
Example two.
例子二。
I stand before this court and declare my innocence.
我站在这个法庭面前，宣布我的清白。
Example three.
例子三。
Together we now stand before this great challenge and we will fight arm in arm to defeat poverty.
我们现在一起站在这个巨大挑战面前，我们将并肩作战，击败贫困。
Right.
对。
So you can see that this is a wonderful phrase to use maybe in a formal speech, right?
所以你可以看到，这是一个很棒的短语，也许可以在正式演讲中使用，对吧？
Right.
对。
Or a wedding again or a formal ceremony.
或者婚礼，或者正式仪式。
Yeah.
是的。
So, and it gives you this idea, this sort of very poetic image of people sort of almost
所以，它给你这种想法，这种非常诗意的画面，人们几乎
standing at the cliff, standing before the, you know, some big change that's about to
站在悬崖边，站在某种即将发生的重大变化面前。
take place.
Exactly.
正是。
So 10 years past the midpoint of a century, the United States has witnessed four major
所以在本世纪中点过去十年的位置，美国见证了四次主要
wars, right?
战争，对吧？
Okay.
好的。
And well, he said, despite the carnage of these conflicts, America is today the strongest,
嗯，他说，尽管这些冲突造成了屠杀，但美国今天是世界上最强大、
the most influential and most productive nation in the world.
最有影响力和最高产的国家。
Okay.
好的。
So a great, great, great structure here.
所以这里有一个非常非常棒的结构。
Despite the carnage of these conflicts, America today is the strongest blah, blah, blah, blah,
尽管这些冲突造成了屠杀，但美国今天是最强大的等等等等等等。
blah, blah, blah.
Right.
对。
Now, let's look at that first word, despite the carnage of these conflicts.
现在，让我们看看第一个词，尽管这些冲突造成了屠杀。
Okay.
好的。
So, carnage, what's that?
那么，carnage，那是什么？
Carnage is like a massacre, right?
Carnage 就像大屠杀，对吧？
Where many people got hurt or killed.
很多人受伤或死亡的地方。
Okay.
好的。
So a pretty violent situation when a lot of people died.
所以是一个相当暴力的情境，很多人死了。
And now why does he use this word despite?
现在他为什么用 despite 这个词？
Okay.
好的。
So he's basically saying even though we had all of this death and violence in this century,
所以他基本上是在说，尽管本世纪有所有这些死亡和暴力，
we're still the greatest nation, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
我们仍然是最伟大的国家，等等等等等等。
Exactly.
正是。
That's exactly it.
就是这样。
I can say, for example, despite the economic crisis the world is going through, our company
例如，我可以说，尽管世界正在经历经济危机，我们公司
has an enormous opportunity to grow and be more profitable.
有着巨大的增长和盈利机会。
Okay.
好的。
Or if we want to take it and imagine we're at a wedding, we might say something like
或者，如果我们想换个场景，想象我们在婚礼上，我们可能会这样说：
this.
这样。
You could say, despite the many difficulties this couple has faced, they have a very bright
你可以说，尽管这对夫妇面临许多困难，但他们有一个非常光明
and happy future together.
和幸福的未来。
Very good.
非常好。
And now if we take a look at the last paragraph, it's very interesting because it's one sentence.
现在，如果我们看最后一段，它非常有趣，因为这是一个句子。
It's a really long sentence.
这是一个非常长的句子。
It's a very long sentence.
So even though it's not a phrase, let's take a look at the punctuation of this paragraph.
所以，虽然这不是一个短语，但让我们看看这段的标点符号。
Okay.
好的。
So Eisenhower starts out by saying, we pray that peoples of all face, all races, all nations
所以，艾森豪威尔一开始说，我们祈祷所有信仰、所有种族、所有国家的人民
may have their great human needs satisfied.
都能满足他们伟大的人类需求。
And then we have a semicolon there, right?
然后那里有一个分号，对吧？
Right.
对。
So why do we have a semicolon?
那么，为什么我们要用分号呢？
Well, here's what he's doing.
嗯，他是这样做的。
He's saying we pray for something.
他说我们祈祷某件事。
And then he's listing the many different things that he's praying for.
然后他列出了他祈祷的许多不同事情。
Okay.
好的。
So it's basically a list.
所以这基本上是一个列表。
Yep.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So we know that when you're writing a list, we commonly use commas between all the things
所以，我们知道当你写一个列表时，我们通常在列表中的所有项目之间使用逗号。
that are in this list.
But here, because they are long and complex ideas, a comma is not enough.
但在这里，因为它们是很长且复杂的想法，逗号是不够的。
You need a semicolon.
你需要一个分号。
Okay.
好的。
So we can see here from the text that the semicolon is a great way to separate ideas,
所以，我们可以从文本中看到，分号是分隔列表中想法、大想法、复杂想法的好方法。
big ideas, complex ideas in a list.
Exactly.
完全正确。
So you can use it and not necessarily have to end your sentence or that each idea become
所以你可以使用它，而不必结束你的句子，或者让每个想法都变成
one sentence.
一个句子。
You can all just make it one big sentence.
你可以把它们都变成一个长句子。
Yep.
是的。
You know, and actually I remember back to high school, Marco, my teacher told me, hey,
你知道吗，实际上我记得高中时，Marco，我的老师告诉我，嘿，
if you throw in a few semicolons into your writing and do it properly, you'll really
如果你在写作中适当加入几个分号，你会真的
impress people.
给人留下深刻印象。
All right.
好的。
So this is good advice that you can take and throw in a couple of semicolons, a little
所以这是一个好建议，你可以采纳，加入几个分号，这里那里加一点
bit of commas here and there, and it'll look like you really know how to write.
逗号，看起来就像你真的知道怎么写。
Yep.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So with that in mind, why don't we listen to what Eisenhower wrote one last time.
那么，考虑到这一点，我们最后再听一次艾森豪威尔写了什么。
We now stand 10 years past the midpoint of a century that has witnessed four major wars
我们现在站在一个世纪中点之后的十年，这个世纪见证了四大国之间的四次主要战争。
among great nations.
Three of these involved our own country.
其中三次涉及我们自己的国家。
Despite the carnage of these conflicts, America is today the strongest, the most influential
尽管这些冲突造成了屠杀，但美国今天是世界上最强大、最有影响力
and the most productive nation in the world.
和最富生产力的国家。
We are understandably proud of this preeminence, yet we realize that America's leadership
我们理所当然地为这种卓越感到自豪，但我们意识到美国的领导地位
and prestige depend not merely upon our unmatched material progress, riches and military strength,
和威望不仅取决于我们无与伦比的物质进步、财富和军事实力，
but on how we use our power in the interests of world peace and human betterment.
还取决于我们如何利用我们的力量来促进世界和平和人类福祉。
Throughout America's adventure in free government, such basic purposes have been to keep the
在美国自由政府的冒险历程中，这些基本目标一直是维护
peace, to foster progress and human achievement, and to enhance liberty, dignity, and integrity
和平、促进进步和人类成就，以及增强人民和国家之间的自由、尊严和正直。
among peoples and among nations.
We pray that peoples of all faiths, all races, all nations may have their great human needs
我们祈祷所有信仰、所有种族、所有国家的人民都能满足他们伟大的人类需求，
satisfied, that those now denied opportunity shall come to enjoy it to the full, that all
那些现在被剥夺机会的人能够充分享受它，所有
who yearn for freedom may experience its spiritual blessings, that those who have freedom will
渴望自由的人都能体验其精神祝福，那些拥有自由的人
understand also its heavy responsibilities, that all who are insensitive to the needs
也能理解其沉重的责任，所有对他人的需求漠不关心
of others will learn charity, that the scourges of poverty, disease, and ignorance will be
的人将学会慈善，贫困、疾病和无知的祸害将
made to disappear from the earth, and that in the goodness of time, all peoples will
从地球上消失，并且在时间的仁慈中，所有人民将
come to live together in a peace guaranteed by the binding force of mutual respect and
在相互尊重和爱的约束力所保证的和平中共同生活。
love.
Now, on Friday noon, I am to become a private citizen.
现在，在周五中午，我将成为一名普通公民。
I am proud to do so.
我为此感到自豪。
I look forward to it.
我期待着它。
Thank you, and good night.
谢谢你们，晚安。
All right, we're back, and we're here again with Pete, our voice actor for the second
好的，我们回来了，我们再次和Pete在一起，他是我们对话第二部分的配音演员。
part of the dialogue.
And Pete, we have a couple more questions for you today.
而Pete，我们今天还有几个问题要问你。
Cool.
酷。
So I hear in Eisenhower's speech that he keeps referencing God.
所以我在艾森豪威尔的演讲中听到他不断提到上帝。
Like he keeps saying, I pray, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
就像他不停地说，我祈祷，等等等等等等。
He said God's speed, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
他说上帝保佑，等等等等等等。
So what's up with that?
这是怎么回事？
Why is he talking about God?
他为什么谈论上帝？
Well, this is a very interesting question.
嗯，这是一个非常有趣的问题。
Traditionally, America has had a really clear boundary between church and state.
传统上，美国在教会和国家之间有一个非常明确的界限。
And you'll hear a lot of rhetoric these days that says, you know, we're a Christian nation,
而如今你会听到很多言论说，你知道，我们是一个基督教国家，
and we were founded as a Christian nation.
我们作为一个基督教国家建立。
Well, that's baloney.
嗯，那是胡扯。
Baloney, so it's not true.
胡扯，所以这不是真的。
At the time when the country was founded 200 years ago, it was overwhelmingly Christian.
在200年前这个国家建立的时候，它绝大多数是基督教徒。
If the founding fathers, as we call them, like George Washington and them, if they had
如果开国元勋，我们这样称呼他们，比如乔治·华盛顿他们，如果他们
wanted a Christian nation, they could have had it.
想要一个基督教国家，他们本可以做到。
They explicitly did not.
他们明确地没有这样做。
And a lot of people since then have gotten that confused.
而自那以后很多人对此感到困惑。
And now when we have a very large Muslim population, we have Buddhists, we have, you know, people
现在当我们有非常大的穆斯林人口，我们有佛教徒，我们有，你知道，各种不同种类的
in all various different kinds of, you know, Mormonism and everything, it's even less possible
人，比如摩门教等等，现在更不可能了。
now.
So I'm kind of baffled when I hear people say that America is a Christian nation.
所以当我听到人们说美国是一个基督教国家时，我有点困惑。
But you even have it now in the coins, like, or on the money, right?
但你现在甚至在硬币上，或者钱上，对吧？
It says in God we trust.
上面写着“我们信仰上帝”。
Right.
对。
That started in the early 20th century.
那始于20世纪初。
I think that was Teddy Roosevelt era.
我想那是西奥多·罗斯福时代。
He opposed that.
他反对那个。
Roosevelt was really opposed to that, but...
罗斯福真的反对那个，但是...
And then what happened?
然后发生了什么？
They approved it.
他们批准了。
Yeah.
是的。
And, you know, people said later, like Eisenhower talking about this stuff, you know, in America
而且，你知道，后来人们说，像艾森豪威尔谈论这些东西，你知道，在美国
we have something called the Pledge of Allegiance, which I don't think you guys probably have.
我们有所谓的效忠誓言，我想你们可能没有。
Not in Canada.
在加拿大没有。
Obviously, you wouldn't do it to America, but to your own.
显然，你不会对美国这样做，而是对你们自己的国家。
It's kind of...
这有点...
Like a salute to the flag, right?
就像向国旗敬礼，对吧？
Yeah, it's a little bit nationalist.
是的，有点民族主义。
I did it growing up.
我小时候做过。
You put your hand over your heart and you face the flag and you say, I pledge allegiance
你把你的手放在你的心上，面对国旗，你说，我宣誓效忠
to the flag of the United States of America and to the republic for which it stands, one
美利坚合众国的国旗和它所代表的共和国，一个
nation under God, indivisible, with liberty and justice for all.
在上帝之下的国家，不可分割，人人享有自由和正义。
That part about one nation under God, that was added in the 50s as a kind of a way of
关于“在上帝之下的国家”那部分，是在50年代添加的，作为一种方式
showing that America is not, quote unquote, a godless communist country.
来表明美国不是所谓的无神论共产主义国家。
Wow.
哇。
Yeah, because communism teaches, you know, no religion.
是的，因为共产主义教导，你知道，没有宗教。
And so they, make sure we're not communist.
所以他们确保我们不是共产主义者。
Okay, but we don't think that, right?
好的，但我们不这么认为，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
I mean, I'm all about tolerance.
我的意思是，我完全支持宽容。
So I think that's kind of absurd.
所以我认为这有点荒谬。
Okay, so what I think is really interesting, though, is that every political speech, every
好的，但我认为非常有趣的是，每一次政治演讲，每一次
time a political leader has to say something publicly, he'll always quote God, right?
政治领袖必须公开说些什么，他总会引用上帝，对吧？
Right.
对。
And they'll often end a speech with, you know, thank you and God bless America or something.
而且他们经常以“谢谢你们，上帝保佑美国”或类似的话结束演讲。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，完全正确。
Which, you know what, for me as a Canadian is really strange.
你知道吗，对我来说作为一个加拿大人，这真的很奇怪。
Like if a Canadian president said, God bless Canada, everyone would, no one would know
就像如果加拿大总统说“上帝保佑加拿大”，每个人都会，没人知道
what to do.
该做什么。
Like, I don't know.
就像，我不知道。
I don't know.
我不知道。
Anyway, I had an ex-girlfriend who was British and she, like Tony Blair started with that
不管怎样，我有一个前女友是英国人，她，就像托尼·布莱尔开始那样
a couple times.
几次。
He said, you know, and God bless us all or something.
他说，你知道，上帝保佑我们所有人或类似的话。
And she was just put off by it.
她对此感到反感。
And she was like, the Brits will never take this.
她说，英国人永远不会接受这个。
And they didn't.
他们确实没有。
No one was impressed.
没有人被打动。
All right.
好的。
Well, an interesting feature of American history, politics and society.
嗯，这是美国历史、政治和社会的一个有趣特点。
So thanks for that insight, Pete.
所以谢谢你的见解，Pete。
Cool.
酷。
My pleasure.
不客气。
Yeah.
是的。
And if you guys have any comments or any suggestions about this lesson or any upcoming lessons,
如果你们对本课或任何即将到来的课程有任何评论或建议，
just let us know.
请告诉我们。
Or American politics in general.
或者一般的美国政治。
I'll try to stop in on the forum and see if I can answer a question or two.
我会尽量在论坛上看看，看看能不能回答一两个问题。
That would be awesome.
那太棒了。
So visit us at EnglishPod.com and Marco, myself and Pete are around to answer your questions.
所以访问我们的EnglishPod.com，Marco、我和Pete都在这里回答你们的问题。
All right.
好的。
We'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里见你们。
Thanks for downloading and goodbye.
感谢下载，再见。
Stay Foreign
保持外国范儿